<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Tobias Schwoerer</title>
    <link>https://schwoererresearch.org/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Tobias Schwoerer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://schwoererresearch.org/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Aquatic invasive species risk management</title>
      <link>https://schwoererresearch.org/project/elodea/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schwoererresearch.org/project/elodea/</guid>
      <description>Effective management of Elodea across large geographic areas relies on detection of new infestations and predictions of its spread. Elodea’s increasing rate-of-spread, combined with limited detection resources, requires agencies to formalize and justify increasingly costly response actions. By better understanding elodea’s invasion processes, multi-agency response coordination can be improved to eradicate or suppress this and other economically damaging invasive aquatic plants. In collaboration with agencies, our research team consisting of Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State of Alaska Salmon and People</title>
      <link>https://schwoererresearch.org/project/salmonstate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schwoererresearch.org/project/salmonstate/</guid>
      <description>Alaska’s wild salmon are essential to Alaska’s cultures and economies and reflect a long tradition of stewardship. However, shifts in climate patterns, access and equity concerns, and other pressures increasingly threaten Alaska salmon and the people who depend on them.The State of Alaska’s Salmon and People (SASAP) project State of Alaska’s Salmon and People (SASAP) projectis a collaboration of researchers, cultural leaders, and others working to bring together integrated, accurate, and up-to-date information that will help to support better salmon decision-making.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>